privacytools.io 2017-11-23

# Data Privacy Policy - About Qwant

## Privacy policy

Last update : 23/02/2017 

Qwant ensures that your privacy is protected, and this is the cornerstone of our philosophy. We don’t use any cookie nor any tracking device that may allow us to track your browsing habits or to establish your profile. You are of course entitled to the rights provided by law (in particular the European legal framework and the French _[loi « Informatique et Libertés » du 7 janvier 1978](https://www.cnil.fr/fr/loi-78-17-du-6-janvier-1978-modifiee)_ ), but we also forbid ourselves from collecting an important amount of data that others collect, which are useless to provide you with the services you need. We never try to find out who you are or what you are personally doing when you use our search engine. When we do need to collect data, we do not disclose nor sell it for commercial or other uses. We use it exclusively to provide you with the services offered by Qwant.

This Privacy Policy is aimed at explaining in further details our ethical approach towards personal data, and at explaining the few cases where we have to collect information about you, the reasons why we collect such data, and the way we might use it. It also presents the security measures that we apply to protect their confidentiality, and reminds your rights and how to exercize them.

### How does Qwant protect your privacy?

We should always ask our search engine what are the personal data that it does _not_ collect _🙂_

As a principle, **Qwant does not collect data about its users when they search**. Plain and simple.

When you use Qwant as a search engine, we don’t put any cookie on your browser that may allow us or others to recognize you or to follow you everywhere on the Internet. We don’t use any tracking device (pixel, fingerprinting…). We don’t collect and we don’t store any history or your searches. When you search, your query is instantly anonymized by being dissociated from your IP address, in accordance with what the French data controller advices. Long story short, what you are doing with Qwant is part of your privacy and we don’t want to know.

Qwant has a Privacy office dedicated to protecting your privacy. It also has a Data Protection Officer (DPO). Both work closely with eachother to ensure that the relevant regulation regarding personal data is applied as strongly as it should.

The DPO keeps an updated register of all processing of personal data made by Qwant for his services. For instance, when you create an account on the site, you can choose to fill in your profile and this is a processing of personal data for which the register will say how data may be kept (and how long), and who can access it. The DPO makes this register available to anyone who asks : [privacy@qwant.com](mailto:privacy@qwant.com).

We commit to do anything we can to ensure the security and confidentiality of our users personal data, including by preventing data damage, loss, or access by unauthorized third parties. Qwant’s URL has the HTTPS header that shows users they communicate with Qwant through a secure channel using the TLS protocol. Technically, TLS ensures users that their data can’t be intercepted by fraud. Moreover, the green lock that you see on most browsers when using Qwant certifies that you are browsing a secure website.

### When do we collect personal data, and why?

Qwant does not require any registration to use its search engine. However, you may want to register an account to sign-in and enjoy advanced functionalities such as the possibility to save search results in favorites, or create Boards.

In such cases, we collect some personal data such as your name, firstname and email address when you register to our services, or when you use forms available on our website. You can modify, correct, and update information that you submit on the website.

Qwant also collects connection data, not associated with your search queries, only to ensure the security of its information system and, if you create or modify Boards, to respect the obligation to identify content creators such as mandated by French law ( _[article 6-II de la Loi pour la confiance en l’économie numérique](https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichTexteArticle.do;?idArticle=LEGIARTI000032400316&cidTexte=LEGITEXT000005789847&dateTexte=20170112)_ ).

**Even when you are connected with an ID, we don’t use any cookie nor any other tracking device** when you browse the site. The only technology that may be installed on your browser, called “local storage”, is used to locally save your settings (language, activation or deactivation of options…). You can delete personal data stored in your “local storage” by deactivating cookies in your browser. However, this deactivation may prevent you from accessing some functionalities of the site, such as your browsing preferences.

Users personal data are collected and processed by Qwant solely for the following purposes:

  * the technical management of the user’s account(s) and available services;
  * the management of information requests and job applications;
  * the management of delisting requests and requests associated with personal data access, rectification, and removal rights;
  * the security of Qwant’s information system;
  * the compliance with legal and regulatory obligations.

### What do we do with this personal data?

Personal data that you transmit are never disclosed or sold by Qwant to third parties, except for job applications that may be shared with recruiting partners, unless you ask us not to. Your data is stored on servers that belong to us and is never send to third-party technical parteners. Our host (as identified in our terms) only provides a secure location for our servers, and can’t access it.

### How long do we keep this personal data?

Users personal data is kept as long as you use the services provided by the site.

For Qwant and Qwant Junior accounts, your data is removed 7 days after you request that the account be deleted. If you use a EDU Qwant Junior account (edu.qwantjunior.com), your data is removed 3 months after the account deletion request. During this period, you can ask that your account be reactivated using your initial username and password.

For data that may be collected when you exercize some rights (access, opposition, rectification, right to be forgotten…), the duration of retention depends on what the law prescribes for each of these rights. Please refer to the next section of this Privacy Policy for details.

For connection data that the information system security department may access, the duration of retention is 6 months.

For Qwant Boards, [French law](https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichTexte.do?cidTexte=JORFTEXT000023646013&categorieLien=id) makes it mandatory to keep some connection data (e.g. user ID used, URL or position, nature of the operation, time…) for one year.

### What are your rights and how can you exercize them?

Qwant is governed by French privacy law, which grants specific rights: right to be forgotten, right to access, right to oppose, right to rectify, or right to suppress incomplete or inaccurate information related to you.

You may exercize such rights by contacting us:

  * sending a postal mail to QWANT – Service juridique, 16 avenue Thiers 06000 NICE ;
  * sending an electronic request to [privacy@qwant.com](mailto:privacy@qwant.com).

#### Right to access

You can ask us if we have any information related to you, and ask us information regarding their processing (for instance, the categories of data we process). This right allows you to ask Qwant to give you all this information.

Information related to this right to access (such as your contact info) are kept one year after Qwant has answered, then removed when such delay is over.

#### Right to rectify or suppress

You may modify or suppress information that you entered in your profile, in your Qwant account of any other service (for instance the Qwant Boards).

Information associated to this right to rectify or suppress (such as your contact info) are kept for one year after Qwant has answered, then removed when such delay is over.

#### Right to oppose

As the name says, the right to oppose allows you to oppose data processing by Qwant. You may, for instance, choose to delete your account.

For job applications, you are entitled to refuse that your data be transmitted or retained.

Information about this right to oppose (such as your contact info) are kept for one year after Qwant has answered, and entirely removed when the legal delay is over (3 years).

#### Right to be forgotten (right to delisting)

It is a specific right that the European Court of Justice (ECJ) has recognized, that Qwant applies fully. When the search query with your full name and firstname delivers results which are untrue, obsolete or excessive, you can request that related web results be delisted. Your request will be processed on a case by case basis, and referenced URLs will be delisted only if the balance of interests does not impose to have the public right of information prevail (for instance if you are an elected representative who is trying to make a controversial statement disappear).

Information about this right to be forgotten (such as your contact info) are kept for one year after Qwant has answered, and entirely removed when the legal delay is over (3 years).

### How about ads? Aren’t they tracked?

Qwant is a free search engine open to anyone. Our main source of revenues comes from ads displayed on Qwant results page.  
But we take pride of doing it while respecting both your privacy and your search experience of Qwant.  
Qwant does not track people, and this is never going to change.

We believe you will possibly find commercials interesting when they are directly related to what you are searching.  
Through their numerous formats, ads have too often taken over the use experience. On Qwant, you will never see intrusive ads that get in the way of what are looking for.  
With such commitments, we hope to demonstrate that such responsible and respectful behavior is possible. We have been working for several month at identifying and designing solutions aligned with those principles. We believe we now have designed a simple and efficient offering by working with the Microsoft Bing ad network.

Therefore, every ad that Qwant displays fully adheres to the values we defend and our quality standards.  
When you use Qwant, no personal information whatsoever is neither captured or transmitted to advertisers.  
In details:  
– No third party cookies  
– No trackers  
– No behavioral targeting  
– No campaigns mixing legit and promotional content (native advertising)

We believe advertising can be a responsible business model.

### How does Qwant index the web?

We continue our efforts to index all the Web diversity. Our crawlers relentlessly visit the global Web to refine our results. Nevertheless, this requires both a lot of resources and time: some parts of the Web are not yet perfectly indexed. In the meantime, our agreement with Microsoft Bing allows us to complement our own results with those of Microsoft Bing to offer the best possible results from all around the Web.
